Chris Roche

phone number removed Dallas, Texas area cmroche@gmail.com chrismroche.com

Summary

Senior Software engineer with leadership experience on fast paced and dynamic programs. An Agile and DevOps expert who has worked as Scrum Master, Product Owner, and Continuous Integration pipeline architect. Key strengths are customer communication and taking core system components through requirements, design, development, and integration phases. Former United States Marine with an active security clearance.

Professional Skills

- Agile/Scrum development methodology
- DevOps pipeline and software continuous integration tools
- Customer interaction and communication
- Software design & architecture
- C, C++, C#, OpenCL, Cuda, Python, Ada programming languages
- Test & Behavior Driven Development
- Windows, Linux, and Real Time & Embedded systems

Experience

May 2017 - Present

Software Engineer, Raytheon Space and Airborne Systems - McKinney, TX

- Software product technical lead, Scrum Master, Product Owner
- Oversees software efforts through various product lifecycle phases and customer milestones
- Lead software architect on a large and complex system
- Regularly assists other engineering disciplines with requirements development, systems design, and technical documentation
- Implemented and maintains software Continuous Integration pipeline to automate build process, unit tests, static analysis, and code documentation
- Lead system integrator on an emerging product, ground and flight tests
- Advanced technical education courses in Software Architecture, Principles of Systems
 Engineering, and Machine Learning
- Multiple Achievement Awards for technical leadership and program contributions

February 2007 – February 2012

Intelligence Team Leader, United States Marine Corps - Camp Lejeune, NC

- Awarded Navy and Marine Corps Achievement Medal for excellence
- Routinely coordinated with and advised military and government agency leaders throughout the world
- Trained and led a ten-person team in an active combat zone

Education

M.S. Data Science

Southern Methodist University November 2020 – Present

B.S. Computer Engineering, Minor in Mathematics

University of North Texas May 2017